Guide to the Cornell University Africana Studies and Research Center records, 1969-1976.
Cornell University Africana Studies and Research Center records
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Cornell University Africana Studies and Research Center records, 1969-1976.
53-1-3363
Cornell University.Africana Studies and Research Center.
.3 cubic ft.
Manuscripts
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Contains course syllabi for courses taught in the 1970s.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
The Africana Studies and Research Center was formally the Afro-American Studies Center.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Publicity items, history, lectures, and other ephemera relating to the center and Africana studies. Contains course syllabi for courses taught in the 1970s.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Cornell University.; Cornell University--Students.; Cornell University--Curricula.; Cornell University--Faculty.; Cornell University.Afro-American Studies Center.
Subjects:
African American college students.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Publicity
  - Publicity Flyers (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Series II. Course Syllabi
  - Education in the Urban Black Communities, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Issues in Contemporary Black Writing and Black Political Thought by Rukudzo Murapa, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Afro-American Writing and Expression and History: Politics of Racism and Segregation- J. Congress Mbata, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Black Resistance- South Africa and North America- J. Congress Mbata; The History of Blacks in Theatre adn Drama in America- C. Bethany Jenkins (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Perspectives in Black Theatre and Dramatic Literature- Chestyn Everett; The African Diaspora and the Black Experience- James Turner, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Communications and Development in Africa- Arnold Gibbons; Psychological Aspects of the Black Experience- Dalton Jones (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Development Seminar- Dalton Jones; Colonialsim and Africanization of Public Administration- R. Murapa (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 20th Century America: Infancy, Family and "The Street"; Teaching and Learning in Black Schools- Dalton Jones (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - An Intro to Modern African Political Systems- Tendai Mutunhu: Swahili Literature- Willie Kamera (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - History of Independent African Nations to 1800 A.D.; 19th Century Resistance Movements; African and Afro-American- John Clarke, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Black Writing and Black Techniques of Survival 1876-1970 J. Mayfield; Black Critique: Towards Defining and Developing a Black Aesthetic- C. Everett, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Afro-American History/ 20th Century- Robert Harris; Racism Social Structure and Social Anlysis- James Turner (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Men and Movements in the Black Urban Ghetto- J. Clarke; The Africans in the Making of the New World- J. Clarke, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Politics and Black Community Organization- James Turner; Infancy, Family and the Community- Dalton Jones (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Black American Writing and Politics- J. Mayfield; Advanced Seminar in Total Black Theatre- C. Everett, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Ideology and Development in East Africa; Contemporary African History- John Higginson (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - History of Afro-American Literature- Bell; Black Politics and the American Political System; The Political Economy of Black America- Bailey, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Themes in African History- Mbata; Slave Trade of Africans- Mutunhu; Blacks in Communication Media and Film Workshop- Gibbons and Bourne, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Political History of Social Development- Riviere; Political Ideology, Planning and Development in Africa- Folson, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Workshop in Teaching about Africa- Mbata; Politics in the Afro-Caribbean World- Riviere; African Literature- Fadahunsi; African Philosophy and the Origins of Major West Religions- ben-Jochannan, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Course listings, 1971,1973,1976 (Box 1, Folder 22)